A few words about how I got started,
سأحدثكم قليلا عن كيف بدأت فى هذا المجال ,
and it has a lot to do with happiness, actually.
وحقيقة إنه يرتبط كثيراُ بالسعادة ,
When I was a very young child, I was extremely introverted
عندما كنت طفلاً صغيراً ، كنت إنطوائيا جداً
and very much to myself.
وكان عالمى يدور حول نفسى فقط .
And, kind of as a way of surviving,
وكطريقة للإستمرار فى الحياة ,
I would go into my own very personal space,
كنت أذهب إلى مكانى الخاص بى ,
and I would make things.
وكنت أصنع أشياء .
I would make things for people
كنت أصنع أشياء للناس
as a way of, you know, giving, showing them my love.
كطريقة للعطاء -- ولإظهار حبى لهم .
I would go into these private places,
كنت أتجه إلى هذه المناطق الشخصية ,
and I would put my ideas and my passions into objects --
وكنت لأحول أفكارى و ومشاعرى إلى أشياء ملموسة ,
and sort of learning how to speak with my hands.
ونوعا ما أتعلم كيف أتكلم بواسطة يداى .
So, the whole activity of working with my hands and creating objects
ولذلك فكل النشاط المبذول بيدى و الأشياء المبتكرة
is very much connected with not only the idea realm,
هى عبارة عن طريقة وصل ليس فقط بين الأفكار التى أحبها ,
but also with very much the feeling realm.
ولكن أيضاً تربط بين المشاعر تجاهها .
And the ideas are very disparate.
ولكن الأفكار مختلفة جداً .
I'm going to show you many different kinds of pieces,
سأريكم الكثير من القطع المختلفة النوع ,
and there's no real connection between one or the other,
ولا يوجد بينهما أى إرتباط حقيقى ,
except that they sort of come out of my brain,
إلا أنهم نوعا ما من إنتاج عقلى ,
and they're all different sort of thoughts that are triggered
وكل هذه الأفكارعبارة عن مجموعة من الإعتقادات و الأفكار المختلطة الناتجة
by looking at life, and seeing nature and seeing objects,
من النظر للحياة ورؤية الطبيعة والأشياء ,
and just having kind of playful random thoughts about things.
ومجرد تكوين بعض المعتقدات العشوائية المرحة حول بعض الأشياء .
When I was a child, I started to explore motion.
عندما كنت طفلاً , بدأت فى إسكتشاف و دراسة الحركة .
I fell in love with the way things moved,
لقد وقعت فى حب الطريقة التى تتحرك بها الأشياء ,
so I started to explore motion by making little flipbooks.
لذلك بدأت فى دراسة الحركة و إكتشافها عن طريق صنع صور متحركة صغيرة فى الكتاب .
And this is one that I did, probably like when I was around seventh grade,
وقد إبتكرت هذه الصور تقريبا و أنا فى الصف السابع ,
and I remember when I was doing this,
وأنا أتذكر أثناء عملى لهذا ,
I was thinking about that little rock there,
كنت أفكر فى هذا الرسم الصغير هناك ,
and the pathway of the vehicles as they would fly through the air,
و أفكر فى الطريقة التى تسير بها الشاحنة التى تكاد تطير فى الهواء ,
and how the characters --
وكبف أن الأشخاص --
(Laughter) --
ضحك
would come shooting out of the car,
تكاد تطير من السيارة ,
so, on my mind, I was thinking about the trajectory of the vehicles.
وعلى هذا كنت أفكر فى طريقة سير السيارات .
And of course, when you're a little kid, there's always destruction.
وبالطبع خلال فترة الطفولة , يتوافر دائما عنصر هدم .
So, it has to end with this --
ويجب أن تنتهى بهذه الطريقة --
(Laughter) --
ضحك
gratuitous violence.
عنف غير مبرر .
So that was how I first started to explore the way things moved,
وكانت هذه هى بداية إستكتشافى لكيفية تحرك الأشياء ,
and expressed it.
والتعبير عنها .
Now, when I went to college,
والآن و عند ذهابى للجامعة ,
I found myself making fairly complicated, fragile machines.
وجدت نفسى أصنع ماكينات معقدة هشة نوعا ما .
And this really came about
وهذا كان نتاج
from having many different kinds of interests.
إمتلاكى العديد من الإهتمامات المختلفة .
When I was in high school, I loved to program computers,
عندما كنت فى المدرسة الثانوية ، كنت مغرما ببرمجة الحواسب الآلية ,
so I sort of liked the logical flow of events.
وقد أحببت نوعا ما تدفق المعلومات المنطقى للأحداث .
I was also very interested in perhaps going into surgery
وقد كنت مهتما أيضا كثيرا بإحتمالية الذهاب إلى مجال الجراحة
and becoming a surgeon,
و أن أصبح جراحا ,
because it meant working with my hands
لأن هذا يعنى أن أتمكن من العمل بيدى
in a very focused, intense way.
بتركيز و دقة شديدة .
So, I started taking art courses,
ولذلك بدأت ألتحق ببرامج الفنون ,
and I found a way to make sculpture
ووجدت طريقة لصنع المنحوتات
that brought together my love for being very precise with my hands,
الشيء الذى جمع بين حبى الشديد لإستخدام يداى بدقة
with coming up with different kinds of logical flows of energy through a system.
وبين المجىء بتدفقات مختلفة منطقية للطاقة من خلال نمط معين .
And also, working with wire -- everything that I did
و أيضا العمل مع الأسلاك -- كل ما صنعته من أعمال
was both a visual and a mechanical engineering decision
كان نتاج لرؤية بصرية و إستخدام للهندسة الميكانيكية
at the same time.
فى نفس الوقت .
So, I was able to sort of exercise all of that.
وبالتالى كنت قادرا نوعا ما على التمرين على كل ذلك .
Now, this kind of machine is as close as I can get to painting.
والآن ، هذا النوع من الماكينات هو أقرب ما يكون إلى رسم لوحة .
And it's full of many little trivial end points,
وهو ملىء بالعديد من النقاط الصغيرة الدقيقة ,
like there's a little foot here that just drags around in circles
كما لو أنها مجرد رجِل صغيرة تتحرك فى دوائر
and it doesn't really mean anything.
وتحديدا إنها لا تعنى أى شىء .
It's really just for the sort of joy of its own triviality.
ولكنها فى الحقيقة مجرد شىء يبعث على السعادة رغم عدم أهميتها .
The connection I have with engineering
الرابط الذى يوجد بينى و بين الهندسة
is the same as any other engineer, in that I love to solve problems.
هو نفس الرابط الذى يوجد مع أى مهندس آخر؛ وهو حبى لحل المسائل .
I love to figure things out,
ورغبتى لإيجاد حلول لها ,
but the end result of what I'm doing is really completely ambiguous.
ولكن النتيجة النهائية لما أفعله تكون مبهمة تماما .
(Laughter)
ضحك
That's pretty ambiguous.
ذلك غامض لحد كبير .
The next piece that is going to come up
القطعة التالية التى ستظهر الأن
is an example of a kind of machine that is fairly complex.
هى مثال على نوع من الماكينة هى معقدة نوعا ما .
I gave myself the problem.
لقد وضعت أمامى المسألة
Since I'm always liking to solve problems,
حيث أننى طالما أحببت حل المسائل ,
I gave myself the problem of turning a crank in one direction,
لقد وضعت أمامى مشكلة تحويل شخص غريب فى سلوكه ليتحرك في اتجاه واحد ,
and solving all of the mechanical problems
وحل كل المسائل الميكانيكية
for getting this little man to walk back and forth.
لجعل هذا الشخص يتحرك للأمام و للخلف .
So, when I started this, I didn't have an overall plan for the machine,
وعندما بدأت ذلك , لم تكن لدى خطة عامة لصنع هذه الآلة ,
but I did have a sense of the gesture,
ولكن كان لدى تخيل للحركة
and a sense of the shape and how it would occupy space.
وتخيل للشكل و كيفية إستغلال الفراغات .
And then it was a matter of starting from one point
وبعد ذلك أصبح الأمر هو البدأ من نقطة واحدة
and sort of building to that final point.
ونوع من البناء للوصول إلى تلك النقطة النهائية .
That little gear there switches back and forth to change direction.
هذا الترس الصغير هناك يتحرك للأمام و الخلف لتغيير الإتجاه .
And that's a little found object.
وهو غرض وجدته و ليس له علاقة بالفن مطلقا .
So a lot of the pieces that I've made,
لذلك فالكثير من أعمالى ,
they involve found objects.
تحتوى على بعض الأغراض الموجودة .
And it really -- it's almost like doing visual puns all the time.
وفى الحقيقة -- كأنى أفوم بعمل لعبة الكلمات متجانسة بصريا ( تورية ).
When I see objects, I imagine them in motion.
عندما أرى الأشياء , أتخيلها فى حاله حركه ,
I imagine what can be said with them.
وأتخيل ما الذى يُمكن أن يُقال من خلالها .
This next one here, "Machine with Wishbone,"
هذه الثانية هنا , هى عبارة عن عظمة طائر على شكل بأرجل ,
it came about from playing with this wishbone after dinner.
وقد ظهرت هذه الفكرة من اللعب بالعظم بعد تناول العشاء .
You know, they say, never play with your food --
وكما يقولون , لا تلعب أبدا بطعامك --
but I always play with things.
ولكنى دائما ما ألعب بالأشياء .
So, I had this wishbone, and I thought,
لذا أمسكت هذه العظمة , وقد خطر لى ,
it's kind of like a cowboy who's been on his horse for too long.
أنها مثل راعى البقر الذى مكث طويلاً على جواده .
(Laughter)
ضحك
And I started to make him walk across the table,
وبدأت أجعله يسير على الطاولة ,
and I thought, "Oh, I can make a little machine that will do that."
وفكرت , "أوه , أننى أستطيع أن أصنع ماكينة ستقوم بذلك "
So, I made this device, linked it up, and the wishbone walks.
ولذلك صنعت هذه الآلة , وجمعتها معا , وأصبحت العظمة تسير ,
And because the wishbone is bone -- it's animal --
ولأنها مجرد عظمة -- حيوان --
it's sort of a point where I think we can enter into it.
وأعتقد أنها نقطة حيث يمكننا أن نبدأ منها .
And that's the whole piece.
وهذه هى القطعة كاملة .
(Laughter)
ضحك
That's about that big.
عبارة عن هذا الحجم .
(Applause)
( تصفيق )
This kind of work is also very much like puppetry,
هذا النوع أيضاً من العمل يشبه كثيراً فن العرائس المتحركة
where the found object is, in a sense, the puppet,
حيث تكون القطعة المُكتشفة , فى مشهد , هى الدمية ,
and I'm the puppeteer at first, because I'm playing with an object.
وأنا مُحركها , فى الأول لأنى ألعب بعنصر ,
But then I make the machine, which is sort of the stand-in for me,
ولكن بعد أن أصنع الآلة , التى تحل محلى كدوبلير نوعا ما .
and it is able to achieve the action that I want.
وبالتالى تكون قادرة على تنفيذ ما أريده .
The next piece I'll show you is a much more conceptual thought,
القطعة التالية التى سأريكم إياها هى أقرب ما تكون إلى فكرة تخيلية ,
and it's a little piece called "Cory's Yellow Chair."
وهى قطعة صغيرة تسمى "مقعد كورى الأصفر"
I had this image in my mind, when I saw my son's little chair,
لقد تخيلت هذه الصورة عندما نظرت إلى كرسى ابنى الصغير ,
and I saw it explode up and out.
وتخيلته ينفجر متحولاً إلى قطع صغيرة متناثرة بعيدا .
And --
و --
so the way I saw this in my mind at first,
ولذا الصورة التى خطرت بمخيلتى فى البداية ,
was that the pieces would explode up and out with infinite speed,
كانت أن هذه القطع سوف تنفجر فى كل الإتجاهات بسرعة فائقة ,
and the pieces would move far out,
وسوف تتناثر بعيداً عن بعضها البعض ,
and then they would begin to be pulled back
وعندها ستبدأ فى التجمع ثانية
with a kind of a gravitational feel,
بسبب فعل الجاذبية و تأثيرها ,
to the point where they would approach infinite speed back to the center.
إلى النقطة التى يعودون منها إلى المركز بسرعة فائقة .
And they would coalesce for just a moment,
وسوف تندمج معا للحظة ,
so you could perceive that there was a chair there.
حتى تستطيع ملاحظة أنه كان هناك كرسى .
For me, it's kind of a feeling about the fleetingness of the present moment,
وبالنسبة لى , هذا يمثل نوعا ما من المرور السريع لهذه اللحظة ,
and I wanted to express that.
وقد أردت التعبير عن ذلك .
Now, the machine is -- in this case, it's a real approximation of that,
الآن , الآلة -- فى هذه الحالة تمثل إقتراب حقيقى من هذا المفهوم ,
because obviously you can't move physical matter
لأنه من البديهى أنه لا يمكن تحريك الأجسام المادية
infinitely with infinite speed and have it stop instantaneously.
إلى ما لا نهاية بسرعة فائقة و جعلها تتوقف فجأة .
This whole thing is about four feet wide,
المساحة كلها لا تتعدى عرض أربعة أقدام ,
and the chair itself is only about a few inches.
والكرسى كاملاً عبارة عن بضعة بوصات .
(Applause)
تصفيق
Now, this is a funny sort of conceptual thing,
الآن هذا نوع ما من شيئ خيالى ,
and yesterday we were talking about Danny Hillis' "10,000 Year Clock."
وبالأمس كنا نتحدث عن ساعة دانى هيليز التى تعود إلى عشرة ألآف عام .
So, we have a motor here on the left,
حيث يوجد لدينا محرك هنا فى الشمال ,
and it goes through a gear train.
ويتحرك من خلال قطار من التروس .
There are 12 pairs of 50:1 reductions,
ويوجد إثنا عشر زوج من التروس المُصغرة بنسبة 50 -1 ,
so that means that the final speed of that gear on the end
وهذا يعنى أن السرعة النهائية لهذا الترس فى النهاية
is so slow that it would take two trillion years to turn once.
تكون بطيئة جداً والتى ستأخذ تريليونى عام لتدور مرة واحدة .
So I've invented it in concrete, because it doesn't really matter.
وقد إخترعتها من الإسمنت لأنه لا يمثل أى فرق تغيير المادة .
(Laughter)
ضحك
Because it could run all the time.
لأنها ممكن أن تدور طول الوقت .
Now, a completely different thought.
والأن , فكرة أخرى مختلفة تماما --
I'm always imagining myself in different situations.
أنا دائما ما أتخيل نفسى فى مواقف مختلفة .
I'm imagining myself as a machine.
أتخيل نفسى كآلة .
What would I love?
فماذا أحب أن أفعل ؟
I would love to be bathed in oil.
أود أن أغُتسل بالزيت .
(Laughter)
ضحك
So, this machine does nothing but just bathe itself in oil.
ولهذا , فهذه الآلة لا تفعل شىء سوى أنها تستحم فى الزيت .
(Applause)
تصفيق
And it's really, just sort of --
وهذا مجرد , نوع من --
for me, it was just really about the lusciousness of oil.
بالنسبة لى , كان الأمر متعلق فقط برائحة الزيت الزكية .
(Laughter)
ضحك
And then, I got a call from a friend
ثم بعد ذلك تلقيت مكالمة من أحد أصدقائى
who wanted to have a show of erotic art,
التى كانت تريد أن تقيم عرضاً مثيراً ,
and I didn't have any pieces.
ولم تكن لدى أى قطع .
But when she suggested to be in the show, this piece came to mind.
ولكن عندما أقترحت أن تكون جزء من العرض ، ظهرت القطعة فى عقلى .
So, it's sort of related, but you can see it's much more overtly erotic.
فتكون نوعا ما مترابطة ، ولكن يمكن أن ترى إثارتها بوضوح أكثر .
And this one I call "Machine with Grease."
وهذه الآلة أطلق عليها " آلة الشحم "
It's just continually ejaculating, and it's --
وهى تستمر فى عمل هذا الصوت , وهى --
(Laughter) --
ضحك
this is a happy machine, I'll tell you.
هذه الآلة سعيدة جداً وسأقول لكم .
It's definitely happy.
إنها سعيدة بالتأكيد .
From an engineering point of view,
من وجهة نظر الهندسة ,
this is just a little four-bar linkage.
هذه عبارة عن آلة صغيرة من قضبان أربعة متصلة .
And then again, this is a found object, a little fan that I found.
وهذا أيضا مجرد , غرض عشوائى . و هو عبارة عن مروحة صغيرة وجدتها .
And I thought, what about the gesture of opening the fan,
وفكرت , فى ما هو الغاية من فتح هذه المروحة ,
and how simply could I state something.
وكيف ببساطة يمكننى الوصول لشىء من خلالها .
And, in a case like this, I'm trying to make something which is clear
وفى هذه الحالة , أحاول أن أصنع شىء يكون واضحاً
but also not suggestive of any particular kind of animal or plant.
ولكن أيضا ألا يشير إلى أى نوع من الحيوان أو الجماد .
For me, the process is very important,
بالنسبة لى , الحركة شىء مهم جداً
because I'm inventing machines,
لأننى أخترع ألات ,
but I'm also inventing tools to make machines,
لكنى أيضا أخترع أدوات لصنع الماكينات ,
and the whole thing is all sort of wrapped up from the beginning.
و الأمر كله من البداية هو عبارة عن مجرد أفكار متداخلة معا .
So this is a little wire-bending tool.
وهذه آلة تثنى سلك صغير .
After many years of bending gears with a pair of pliers,
بعد عدة سنوات من تقويس التروس بإستخدام الكماشة ,
I made that tool, and then I made this other tool
و قد صنعت هذه الآلة , وبعد ذلك لقد صنعت هذه الآلة الأخرى
for sort of centering gears very quickly --
لتجميع التروس فى الوسط بسرعة ,
sort of developing my own little world of technology.
نوع من التطوير لعالمى التكنولوجى الصغير .
My life completely changed when I found a spot welder.
لقد تغيرت حياتى تماما عندما وجدت آلة للحام المعادن بإستخدام قوس كهربى فى نقطة .
(Laughter)
ضحك
And that was that tool.
وهذه هى الآلة .
It completely changed what I could do.
لقد غيرت تماما ما كنت أستطيع أن أفعله
Now here, I'm going to do a very poor job of silver soldering.
وها أنا الأن سأقوم بعمل بسيط للغاية للحام بالفضة .
This is not the way they teach you to silver solder when you're in school.
هذه ليست هى الطريقة التى يدرسوها لكم للحم بالفضة فى المدرسة .
I just like, throw it in.
أنا فقط أحب إستخدامها .
I mean, real jewelers put little bits of solder in.
أعتقد , أن الصائغين الفعليين يستخدمون القليل من اللحام فى أعمالهم .
So, that's a finished gear.
هذا ترس مُنتهى صنعه .
When I moved to Boston,
عندما انتقلت إلى بوسطن ,
I joined a group called the World Sculpture Racing Society.
لقد انضممت إلى جمعية المتسابقين بإستخدام التماثيل المنحوتة .
(Laughter)
ضحك
And the idea, their premise was that we wanted to show
والفكرة الأساسية , كانت نظريتهم التى أردنا أن نظهرها
pieces of sculpture on the street,
بعض المنحوتات فى الشارع .
and there'd be no subjective decision about what was the best.
ولم يكن هناك قرار حاسم عن كون أيهم أفضل
It would be -- whatever came across the finish line first would be the winner.
ولكن الفائز هو من يصل إلى خط النهاية أولا .
(Laughter)
ضحك
So I made -- this is my first racing sculpture,
لذلك صنعت -- هذه أول منحوتة سباق لى ,
and I thought, "Oh, I'm going to make a cart,
وفكرت , فى " أنى سوف أصنع عربة صغيرة
and I'm going to have it --
وسوف أحصل بالفعل عليها --
I'm going to have my hand writing 'faster,'
وسوف أكتب ( أسرع ) ,
so as I run down the street, the cart's going to talk to me
وفى حين ما كنت أسير فى الشارع , كانت العربة تتحدث لى
and it's going to go, 'Faster, faster!' "
و كانت تقول لى ( أسرع , أسرع ! ) "
So, that's what it does.
وهذا ما تفعله .
(Laughter)
ضحك
But then in the end, what I decided
ولكن فى النهاية , ما قررته ,
was every time you finish writing the word,
أنه كل مرة أنتهى من كتابة الكلمة ,
I would stop and I would give the card to somebody on the side of the road.
سوف أتوقف و أعطى الورقة لأحد المارة على الطريق
So I would never win the race because I'm always stopping.
ولذلك لن أتمكن أبدا من الفوز فى السباق لأنى دائماً ما أتوقف
But I had a lot of fun.
ولكنى حظيت بالكثير من المتعة .
(Applause)
تصفيق
Now, I only have two and a half minutes -- I'm going to play this.
والآن , لدى دقيقتان ونصف فقط -- سأعرض لكم هذا .
This is a piece that, for me, is in some ways
هذه القطعة بالنسبة لى بطريقة ما
the most complete kind of piece.
الأكثر إكتمالاً .
Because when I was a kid, I also played a lot of guitar.
لأننى عندما كنت طفلاً , كنت ألعب كثيرا بالجيتار .
And when I had this thought,
وعندما جائتنى هذه الفكرة ,
I was imagining that I would make --
كنت أتخيل أننى أستطيع أن أصنع --
I would have a whole machine theater evening,
أستطيع أن أصنع مسرح مسائى آلى ,
where I would -- you would have an audience,
حيث يمكننى -- العثور على مستمعين ومشاهدين ,
the curtain would open, and you'd be entertained by machines on stage.
الستائر سوف تفتح , وسوف تستمتع كثيرا بالآلات التى على المسرح .
So, I imagined a very simple gestural dance
لذلك تخيلت رقصة بسيطة جداً
that would be between a machine and just a very simple chair, and ...
والتى ستكون بين آلة وكرسى بسيط جداً ...
When I'm making these pieces, I'm always trying to find a point
عندما أصنع هذه الآلات ، أحاول دائما أن أجد نقطة ما
where I'm saying something very clearly and it's very simple,
أستطيع من خلالها أن أقول شىء واضح و بسيط جداً ,
but also at the same time it's very ambiguous.
ولكن فى نفس الوقت يكون غامض جداً .
And I think there's a point between simplicity and ambiguity
وأعتقد أنه يوجد خط رفيع بين البساطة و الغموض
which can allow a viewer to perhaps take something from it.
والذى قد يسمح للمشاهد بإستنباط فكرة ما منه .
And that leads me to the thought that all of these pieces
وهذا جعلنى أكتشف أن كل هذه القطع
start off in my own mind, in my heart,
قد بدأت كفكرة فى عقلى , فى قلبى .
and I do my best at finding ways to express them with materials,
وأفعل كل ما أستطيع كى أستطيع التعبير عنها بإستخدام أشياء مادية ملموسة ,
and it always feels really crude.
وهذا شىء فى منتهى الصعوبة والبدائية .
It's always a struggle,
ويمثل بالنسبة لى صراع شديد ,
but somehow I manage to sort of get this thought
ولكنى بطريقة ما أنجح فى تحويل هذه الفكرة
out into an object, and then it's there, OK.
إلى شىء مادى ملموس , وأجدها أمامى , أوك .
It means nothing at all.
لا تعنى شىء على الإطلاق .
The object itself just means nothing.
هذا الشىء فى حد ذاته لا يعنى مطلقا أى شىء ,
Once it's perceived, and someone brings it into their own mind,
وبمجرد أن تُفهم دلالته , ويفهم أحد ما ما هو المقصود به ,
then there's a cycle that has been completed.
سرعان ما تكتمل الدائرة .
And to me, that's the most important thing
وبالنسبة لى هذا هو أهم شىء
because, ever since being a kid, I've wanted to communicate my passion and love.
لأنه منذ أن كنت صبيا , وأردت دائماً أن أشارك عاطفتى و حبى ,
And that means the complete cycle of coming from inside,
وذلك يُعنى الدائرة الكاملة التى تخرج من داخلى
out to the physical, to someone perceiving it.
و تنتهى عند المُتلقى , عندما يلتقط شخص ما ما أقوله .
So I'll just let this chair come down.
وسأنزل هذا الكرسى الآن .
(Applause)
تصفيق
Thank you.
شكرا لكم